8list.ph 2019-03-31

# Privacy – 8List.ph

I.D.8 respects the individual’s right to privacy. I.D.8 is committed to protect the confidentiality of your personal information thus it has adapted necessary measures to secure it.  I.D.8 is bound to comply with the Data Privacy Act of 2012 (RA 10173), its Implementing Rules and Regulations and relevant issuance of the National Privacy Commission. ** **

This Privacy Notice discloses the privacy practices for I.D.8 sites. By accessing it, you are consenting to our collection and use of information in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

I.D.8 sites, which includes 8List.ph, WindowSeat.ph and BiteSized.ph, primarily provide information about life, food and travel. The information may include news, articles, images, photos and videos.

####  **What information do we gather about you?**

You do not have to create an account or provide us with any personal information to access the I.D.8 sites. However, we may ask for some personal details if you wish to access some of our services.

To receive our newsletters you will be asked the following personal information: name, and email address.

To join an I.D.8 site promo you may be asked for your Facebook, Twitter and/or Instagram account/s. If you win in the promo, a private message will be sent asking for your name, address, phone number.

We and our third-party vendors collect certain information regarding your access to our sites, such as the page visited, your IP address and browser type.  We may use your IP address to identify the general geographic area from which you are accessing this site.

####  **What do we use your information for?**

We use your information for marketing purposes and to ensure that you get the best experience on our sites.

We also use the information gathered from you for systems administration purposes, abuse prevention, and to track user trends, and for the other purposes described in this notice. If you send us an email, post on our Facebook page or Twitter account, the email address, Facebook or Twitter account you provide may be used to send you information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions. We will not share, sell or authorize any third party to use your email address and social media accounts for commercial purposes without your permission.

Usage information may be shared with third-party vendors to the extent necessary to provide and improve web services or other communications to users. For example, we use Google Analytics to generate reports on site usage, web traffic, user behavior, and user interests in order to optimize our website for our visitors.

We may also provide your information to third parties in the following circumstances: (1) when you have given consent; (2) if it is in response to subpoenas, court orders or legal processes; (3) a requirement to fulfill a service that you have subscribed to; (4) detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues; or (5) protect our rights and safety and the rights and safety of our users or others.

####  **How is this information collected?**

Google, Facebook and other third parties may use cookies, and similar technologies to collect or receive information from this website and elsewhere on the internet and use that information to provide measurement services and target ads. For more information on Google Analytics privacy policy, visit <https://privacypolicies.com/blog/privacy-policy-google-analytics/> and for Facebook, visit <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>

You may choose not to give your personal information, however I.D.8 may not be able to provide the service that you may require.

####  **Cookies**

Cookies are small files that are stored on your computer (unless you block them). We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. You may disable cookies through your individual browser options.

####  **Other Websites and Cookies**

From I.D.8 sites, you may subscribe to our newsletter, by clicking on the _mailchimp.com_ link and you will be led to MailChimp landing page, where you will be asked for your email address.

This website may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. Cookies may be set by parties other than us. These “third-party cookies” may, for example, originate from websites such as Twitter, Facebook, YouTube or other social media services for which our website has implemented “plug-ins” of. Since the cookie policies of these sites change over time, you should determine their policies by visiting the privacy policy pages of these sites directly.

####  **Information Protection**

I.D.8 has reasonable administrative, physical and technical security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure.

I.D.8 protects your personal information through:

  * Confidentiality requirements and data privacy training of our associates;
  * Document storage security policies;
  * Security measures to control access to our systems and premises;
  * Limitations on access to personal information;
  * Strict selection of third party data processors; and
  * Electronic security systems, such as firewalls and data encryption.

####  **Storage and Transmission**

Personal information is stored in the I.D.8 database cloud. Back up of the personal information is kept in secure physical location.

####  **Retention Period**

Data will only be retained until they are still relevant for I.D.8. In case when a retention period is provided, all records after such period will be securely disposed of.

####  **Data Subject Rights**

You have the following rights as data subjects:

  * Right to be informed what personal information I.D.8 holds about you and what it is used for
  * Right to reasonable access your personal information
  * Right to object to the processing of your personal information
  * Right to update the personal information the I.D.8 holds or rectify inaccurate data
  * Right to erasure or blocking
  * Right to damages
  * Right to data portability
  * Right to file a complaint

You may request access to your personal information, and/or have it corrected, erased or blocked on reasonable grounds.  I.D.8 will consider the request and reserves the right to deal with the matter in accordance with law.

####  **Children’s Privacy**

Our service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”). ** **

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

####  **Amendment/Modification of Data Privacy Policies**

I.D.8 reserves the right to modify/amend this notice at any time in its sole discretion and will publish such modification in our sites. The modification shall take effect immediately upon posting.

Queries and complaints can be directed to the Editor at telephone number (+632) 6597233 or email at hello@id8.com.ph.
